austrian.com 2019-05-14

# Privacy Policy austrian.com Profil / (AirManager)

##  Preamble 

With the following Privacy Policy, Austrian Airlines AG would like to clarify to users of the austrian.com profile what kind of personal data is processed within it.

In addition, the Terms and Conditions of Use of the austrian.com profile and the General Conditions of Carriage for the operation of flights both apply.

For reasons of easier legibility, this Privacy Policy does not make a distinction between male and female persons. The relevant terms apply in all cases to both sexes, in line with gender equality.

##  1\. Controller 

Austrian Airlines AG (Office Park 2, PO Box 100, 1300 Vienna Airport, Austria; hereinafter also “we” or “us”) hereby informs you about the processing of your personal data as part of your use of our austrian.com profile.

When we hereinafter refer to the Lufthansa Group, this also means the airlines [Lufthansa](http://www.lufthansa.com/), [SWISS International Airlines AG](http://www.swiss.com/), Austrian Airlines AG, [Eurowings GmbH](http://www.eurowings.com/) and [Miles & More GmbH](http://www.miles-and-more.com/), and other companies of the Lufthansa Group.

If you have further questions about data protection in connection with your austrian.com profile, please contact our Data Protection Officers via the contact details provided under the section “Rights of Data Subjects”.

##  2\. Data subjects 

Data subjects to whom this Privacy Policy applies are natural persons who have an austrian.com profile.

##  3\. Security has the highest priority 

Security has the highest priority, according to the Austrian Airlines AG creed. This creed most certainly also applies to the handling of personal data in our company.

You entrust us with much of your personal data, whether in the course booking a flight, checking-in or ordering our newsletter. It is an important concern for us that we handle your personal data with the greatest care and protect your privacy. Data protection is taken into account in our business processes at all times.

By using your austrian.com profile you agree to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy applies to the appearance of this website. The pages in this website may contain links directing you to other providers both within and out of Austrian Airlines AG, to which this Privacy Policy does not apply. Austrian Airlines does not undertake any liability for the content of other websites and providers. Please note that different data protection regulations apply when you leave this website.

We use the services of selected data processors for the technical and organisational implementation of our website. These are contractually obliged to process the obtained personal data solely according to our instructions.

##  4\. Registration at austrian.com 

The austrian.com profile enables you to store your personal data with Austrian Airlines AG so that subsequent flight bookings can be processed more quickly and easily.

Registration for an austrian.com profile is voluntary and free of charge, and thus can only take place with your explicit consent. In the event of booking flights, prior registration for an austrian.com profile is only required for special flight purchase conditions, namely ABO and CNR. ABO refers to coupons which are purchased and used for a specific flight route at a specific price and is only available in selected countries. CNR refers to special fares used for corporate clients.

##  5\. Types of data 

Users may provide the following personal data during registration:

  * title, first name, surname,
  * date of birth,
  * e-mail address, contact address (street, town and postcode), telephone number,
  * frequent flyer programme,
  * meal preference (requested menu),
  * preferred departure airport,
  * preferred language and
  * credit card data.

For registration, it is only compulsory to provide an e-mail address and a password.

In addition, registered users of the austrian.com profile have the option of providing the title, first name, surname and e-mail address of those travelling with them. In such cases, the user is obliged to obtain the consent of the people travelling with them and ensure the lawful transfer of personal data to Austrian Airlines AG.

If you enter data about people travelling with you during registration, please note that you must have the required power of representation to do so and you must be authorised to store their personal data in your austrian.com profile.

Every user of the austrian.com profile is able to amend or delete the personal data they have disclosed or subsequently change or cancel the booking of services and flights.

Please note that your passenger data is stored independently of you having an austrian.com profile. In principle, the retention period is three years, unless other statutory or legitimate interests prevent the erasure of such data.

##  6\. Purposes of your austrian.com profile and of data processing 

The austrian.com profile is designed to make Austrian Airlines AG online services easier and more convenient to use. This includes:

  * a simplified flight booking process,
  * the use of additional booking services, such as seat reservations, online check-in, in-flight entertainment, etc.,
  * managing flight bookings, booking changes or cancellations,
  * taking advantage of offers from the Lufthansa Group and our partner companies (i.e. other airlines with which Austrian Airlines cooperates) to help us provide you with further offers, and
  * optional personalised information, offers and advertising.

### 6.1. Booking flights

When you book a flight via your austrian.com profile, the following personal data is processed:

  * title, first name, surname,
  * date of birth,
  * e-mail address, contact address (street, town and postcode), telephone number,
  * frequent flyer programme,
  * meal preference (requested menu),
  * preferred departure airport,
  * preferred language and
  * credit card data.

Irrespective of the travel destination, the following personal data may or must be given:

  * date of birth
  * nationality and passport data
  * frequent flyer number
  * your specific service requests (e.g. meal preferences, transport assistance, accompanying assistance, etc.)
  * Visa data

We only process your personal data in order to fulfil the carriage contract, to issue your desired flight ticket and to send you a booking confirmation. In addition, we process your personal booking data solely on the basis of legal provisions or with your consent. If you provide us with any personal health information when booking your flights so that we can provide you with the relevant assistance in accordance with your medical needs, this data will only be processed for the provision of services and/or shared with third parties (e.g. airports, security checks, etc.) for the provision of services. Any medical data entered for the provision of services is not stored in your austrian.com profile.

If you use other services on our website relating to the flight (e.g. downloading e-Journals or using pre-flight shopping), the personal data collected is only processed for the performance of the contract.

If you carry out the purchase of a flight ticket not only for yourself but also for a person travelling with you, please note that you must have the relevant power to represent.

Please note that your passenger data is stored independently of you having an austrian.com profile. In principle, the retention period is three years, unless other legal or legitimate interests prevent the erasure of such data.

### 6.2. Online check-in

When you use online check-in, we process the following personal data about you:

  * name and booking code
  * contact details (e-mail address, telephone number)
  * your specific service requests (e.g. meal preference, transport assistance, accompanying assistance, etc.)

We only process your personal data for the performance of the carriage contract. Please note that your passenger and check-in data is stored independently of you having an austrian.com profile. In principle, the retention period is three years, unless other legal or legitimate interests prevent the erasure of such data.

### 6.3. Managing flight bookings

You have the option of personally managing your flights in your austrian.com profile under the heading “My bookings”. You can thus view current flight bookings, and change or cancel them in compliance with the conditions of carriage. You can also view completed or cancelled flight bookings in your profile, or look for individual flights using our search function by entering the booking reference. This gives you the option of getting an overview of your booking history.

In principle, your booking history goes back three years. Older flight bookings are deleted automatically after three years, unless other legal or legitimate interests prevent deletion of such data.

### 6.4. Optional: Personalised information, offers and advertising

If you have explicitly consented to the analysis of your personal data and the receipt of communications from Austrian Airlines AG, you will receive personalised information, offers and advertising from Austrian Airlines AG via e-mail, SMS, messenger services and telephone.

By registering for an austrian.com profile, you may give your consent to allow Austrian Airlines AG to analyse your consumption and usage behaviour in order to provide you with personalised information and offers which are relevant to you and customised in accordance with your personal preferences. Analysis takes place by combining all your consumption and usage data that is legally processed by Austrian Airlines AG and other companies of the Lufthansa Group in customer profiles (e.g. Lufthansa ID or Miles & More programme). Your personal analysis data is only processed within the Lufthansa Group and is not sold to third parties.

The term “analyse” is considered to mean that the Lufthansa Group uses the aggregated consumption and usage data, and calculates probabilities with the help of automated analysis models, which form the basis for selecting recommendations and offers that suit your interests.

By analysing your consumption and usage behaviour, we make personalised recommendations, e.g. your next travel destination, arrange additional services (ancillary services such as FlyNet on board, rental car offers or other offers relating to your trip) based on your personal preferences, and provide you with information about services which are of interest to you within the scope of pre-flight, post-flight and push messages, via e-mail, SMS and messenger services. In addition to offers and information from Austrian Airlines AG, the personalised messages also include offers and information from the Lufthansa Group and our partner airlines.

Conducting this analysis enables Lufthansa Group companies to develop specific processes on their websites, with results customised to your personal interests. This may result, for instance, in a simplified booking process with your data appearing already pre-completed in the booking form, or you receiving user-specific information before, during and after a flight trip with Austrian Airlines AG, e.g. gate changes, recommendations for specific flights, information on baggage conditions and promotional and non-promotional offers for services from the Lufthansa Group (e.g. seat reservations or Business Class upgrades). In addition, we analyse your click behaviour as part of electronic communications (e.g. whether you have opened the electronic communication and when).

The menu preferences, additional services for health reasons, passport data or payment data provided in your austrian.com profile or in the course of a booking are processed solely for the performance of the contract on the basis of explicit consent or statutory obligation. They are not processed for **analytical purposes**.

**You can revoke your consent to the analysis of your personal data at any time without giving reasons.** You can still use your austrian.com profile without any restrictions. If you also wish to erase your austrian.com profile, please note the further information under the section “Erasing and deactivating your austrian.com profile”. 

##  7\. Linking a frequent flyer programme 

You can add a frequent flyer programme offered by our partner airlines to your austrian.com profile during or after the registration process. You can find out who our partner airlines are during or after registration by using the drop-down menu. If you link a frequent flyer programme to your profile, your frequent flyer PIN number is also processed in addition to the aforementioned personal data outlined under “Types of data”.

Austrian Airlines AG is the co-publisher of the Miles & More programme. If you are also a member of the Miles & More programme, we ask you to take into account that your austrian.com profile is currently not linked and synchronised with your Miles & More account. This means that you must give or revoke consent to the processing of personal data or electronic communication separately in your austrian.com profile and in your Miles & More account. We therefore request that you consult the data protection information for Miles & More GmbH.

##  8\. Electronic communication 

If you have given your consent during the registration process, you will receive information, offers, customer satisfaction surveys and newsletters, including from partner companies, relating to the subject of travel from Austrian Airlines AG by e-mail, SMS, messenger services and telephone.

You will only receive electronic communications in connection with your austrian.com profile if you have consented to the analysis of your data under the section “Personalised information, offers and advertising”.

In your austrian.com profile, you can also revoke your consent to receive electronic communications for individual areas (e.g. only e-mail communication or only telephone communication). In addition, you can revoke your consent at any time in any e-mail or other electronic communication by clicking on the “Unsubscribe function”. The use of your austrian.com profile will not be affected or restricted in any way by unsubscribing from the newsletter.

##  9\. Transfer of personal data to third parties 

The personal data you disclosed in your austrian.com profile when successfully booking a flight will only be shared with third parties (e.g. operating airlines, airports, etc.) for the performance of contractual obligations.

The transmission of personal data to domestic and foreign courts, authorities or other state institutions will only be carried out in accordance with enforceable legal requirements.

##  10\. Legitimate interests 

If we process your data in our legitimate interests, in addition to the purposes stated above, this means the following:

  * To claim, defend or enforce legal claims,
  * For the transparency and further development of business processes subject to the stated retention periods.

##  11\. Review of payment transactions 

Austrian Airlines AG reviews payment transactions in connection with flight bookings to prevent fraud and other improper use. For this purpose, Austrian Airlines AG uses both internal and external resources. If specific fraudulent activities are detected, Austrian Airlines AG reserves the right to share information, including personal data, with other companies within the Lufthansa Group.

##  12\. Use of cookies 

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer. If you access a website as a user, the cookies are stored on your operating system once consent is given. These cookies contain a characteristic sequence of digits that allow the browser you use to be identified clearly the next time you access the website.

As a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. You can deactivate or restrict the transfer of cookies by changing the settings. Cookies already stored can be deleted at any time. Please note that by deleting temporary files and cookies, you must renew your cookie settings again. If you deactivate the cookies for our website, it may no longer be possible to use all the features of our website.

If you would like to carry out this deactivation or change your privacy settings, please click here.

For further information, please read our Cookie Policy.

##  13\. Using the austrian.com profile 

You may only use the austrian.com profile in accordance with the Terms and Conditions of Use and only for the aforementioned purposes. In particular, the austrian.com profile must not be used for commercial purposes and for the reproduction of online services or other advertising content offered by Austrian Airlines AG without the consent of Austrian Airlines AG.

Please note that, irrespective of the Terms & Conditions of Use of the austrian.com profile, our General Terms & Conditions of Carriage and the data protection provisions attached thereto apply at all times in relation to the booking and operation of flights.

##  14\. Accurate and updated austrian.com profile information 

You can modify and update your personal information yourself at any time by going to Profile Settings. You are personally responsible for ensuring that the information is accurate and up to date.

##  15\. Erasing and deactivating an austrian.com profile 

You can erase your own austrian.com profile at any time without needing to provide a reason.

Your austrian.com profile will initially be temporarily deactivated and erased during the next deletion process and it can then no longer be used.

Please note that your passenger data is stored independently of you having an austrian.com profile. In principle, the retention period is three years, unless other legal or legitimate interests prevent the deletion of such data.

Austrian Airlines AG reserves the right to deactivate or erase any austrian.com profile in the event of a violation of the Terms and Conditions of Use. Moreover, the functionalities of the austrian.com profile will be continuously improved. In such cases, Austrian Airlines AG reserves the right to implement improvements and amendments to the functionalities or the Terms and Conditions of Use at any time without prior notification. If you do not agree with the amendments to the functionalities or the Terms and Conditions of Use, your austrian.com profile will be deactivated, subject to a reasonable cancellation period, and subsequently erased.

Austrian Airlines AG further reserves the right to deactivate your austrian.com profile at any time. In this case, your austrian.com profile will then be deleted.

##  16\. Data security 

Austrian Airlines AG implements technical and organisational data security procedures to protect your personal data against incidental and wilful manipulation, loss and destruction, or against access by unauthorised persons. Data security measures at Austrian Airlines AG are continuously evolving to ensure our technical security procedures reflect the latest standards in technological development. At the same time, our staff at Austrian Airlines AG in the data security and data protection divisions undergo training and are subject to organisational procedures designed for secure data processing.

##  17\. Data subjects’ rights 

It is an important concern for Austrian Airlines AG to make our data processing processes clear and transparent. It is therefore important that our customers are not only able to withdraw their consent, but also to exercise the following rights they have:

  * Right of access 
  * Right of rectification of their personal data 
  * Right to erasure 
  * Right of restriction of processing 
  * Right to data portability 

You must submit your application for access with proof of your identity (scan or copy of an official photo ID) in writing using our online form. You can also send your application for access by post to:

Austrian Airlines AG  
Legal Office - Data Protection  
Office Park 2  
PO Box 100  
1300 Vienna Airport  
Austria

Further information on the erasure of your austrian.com profile is available in the section “Erasing or deactivating your austrian.com profile”.

You can correct any incorrect personal data yourself at any time by going to Profile Settings in your austrian.com profile.

If you have any other concerns regarding data protection law, please contact us by post at the address given above or contact our company’s Data Protection Officer using our online form.

You also have the right to file a complaint with the Data Protection Authority as the supervisory authority with jurisdiction. The data protection authority with jurisdiction for Austrian Airlines AG is:

Austrian Data Protection Authority  
Barichgasse 40-42  
1030 Vienna  
Telephone: +43 (0) 52 152 – 0  
E-mail: [dsb@dsb.gv.at](mailto:dsb@dsb.gv.at)

##  18\. Disclaimer 

This Privacy Policy only applies to the processing of personal data when using your austrian.com profile. This Privacy Policy does not cover other websites, in particular third-party websites. If you leave the austrian.com profile website, we ask you to consult the validity of the applicable data protection provisions.
